One of the worst things you can do in
business is send people to your website
and
just hope that they're going to do
business with you.
And there is the inflammatory statement in
which I start the video with for you to
think, "You're an idiot, James,
and you don't know what you're on about."
But if
you're anyone that's ever on social media,
said, "Hey, click the link in my bio,"
or, "Head to my website,"
and then quite literally made zero
sales, I'm going to explain why that is.
Now,
I'm just a random bloke on the internet
sat in front of a camera with his
microphone,
so I need something called an appeal to
authority.
So what we have here
is a screenshot of my Stripe.
This month I've done about 270,000 US
dollars using
exactly this. Well,
I'll attribute about 200,000 of
that to this very thing
I'm going to teach you.
So the majority of every single sale I've
made over the
last four weeks is because of this detail
the majority of people still
overlook. Now,
you're already going to be thinking,
"We know what you're going to
say, James. Via email. We get it.
You like email marketing.
We need to start an email list." Well,
guess what? I've got an email list.
And to drive the point home,
I'm not just going to give you one or two,
I'm going
to give you 10 reasons,
10 individual stories, analogies,
metaphors, parables,
whichever way you want to see it, so
that for once you might
actually believe me
and start doing things differently.
And then in a few months' time,
or maybe even a few weeks,
you'll make a shitload
of sales and go, "Do you know what?
That handsome English chap on the internet
was
right all this time." First point.
The date today is December 2nd.
How many of you engaged in Black Friday
deals in the last
week via email? Often,
you would've got re-engaged.
You might have bought protein from a
company, they come in and go, "Hey,
protein
40% off." You go,
"Might as well stock up."
Or Amazon realizing that I bought a rig
for my camera,
so they come with all these other
different types of camera rig
equipment saying, "James, hey,
do you want access to the Black Friday
deal?" Sneaky
bastards.
It would have been raining down on you
from any business that you
previously had done business with.
But when it comes to re-engaging someone
or getting someone to buy from you that
maybe even hasn't bought before,
the big companies use email,
and I'm going to
explain why. First one of which,
I know I've used this one quite a few
times, let's
get it off the bat.
If you want to get laid,
when you go to the club or the bar,
don't worry about taking the person home,
worry about getting their number.
Because statistically speaking, sure,
they might want to go home and do
that night,
but they've probably got a night out with
their friends, staying at a mate's,
whatever it is, and logistically speaking,
for you both to be aligned at that very
point in time isn't likely. But
if you can get that person's number,
then after
that night out on a Monday evening
when no one's got any plans,
you can have a
night that perfectly aligns where you go
meet in a bar together and you give each
other the whole night to talk
and figure each other out to see whether
or not you
want to [smacks lips] or more.
It's almost naive to
assume just because you want to have sex
and you see that person at the bar, that
everything should all fall into line for
you.
Ultimately, the person
that goes to the club
and gets the most numbers can arrange
the most dates,
and the person who goes on the most dates
will get their end away
the most. So that's number one.
Number two.
This week,
been strategizing with a Brazilian
Jiu-Jitsu black belt called Luke,
and we'll overlay a little bit of footage
here of him kicking arse on Tuesday and
manhandling me.
Luke produces more high-level killer
athletes in
jiu-jitsu in Australia than anyone else,
and he's been making the mistake of
sending people to his website to sign up.
And it's worked,
but not to the size of
which he would like or he deserves for the
level of coaching that he has.
So I've said to him to stop sending people
to the
website and instead build an email list.
Because the process of getting someone
onto your email list can be the very thing
that converts someone to wanting to do
business with you.
So let's keep this Brazilian jiu-jitsu
analogy.
Luke's there thinking, "Okay,
rather than sending people to my website,
which I've
been doing for quite a while,
I'm going to start sending people to an
email list.
How am I going to do that?
I'm going to reference pop culture,
and I'm going to see
which high-level submissions at
competition are causing a wave
or causing people to talk about it.
Oh my god,
Joseph Chen got leg locked at CGI by Lucas
Barbosa. I haven't seen
that submission in years." The next day,
you need to react,
and you need to turn up on social media
going, "Hey, guys, let me teach you that
submission." You do 30 to 45 seconds,
but you say, "By the way, if
you want to see a 10-minute breakdown of
how to get this submission, but not just
how to get that submission,
and how you can hit unsuspecting training
partners the next time you're at training
with this submission that's really going
to surprise them,
then DM me the word knee or leg, and
I will send you a link to where you can
get the instructional." And then that
automated message through ManyChat comes
through and it says, "Hey, thank you very
much. Give me your best email address,
and I will send over the instructional.
Just to let you know,
I'll be adding you to my email list."
That's a fair exchange
of goods.
I'm going to get a 10-minute demonstration
of a leg lock that potentially
I could watch to go to tonight's training
and tap someone that's a higher grade
than me just for my email address.
Bargain.
They watch the video, and whilst in
that 10 minutes, they're going,
"Do you know
what?
This guy is exceptional at explaining
techniques and instructionals.
This guy is better than my coach.
This person is helping me understand in
a way that I've not realized before."
That person may have had no intention
ever of joining Luke's online program,
but after 10 minutes, they're partially
indoctrinated. Then the next day,
they get engaged by Luke with an email
saying, "I
don't just want to make you better at
jiu-jitsu.
I want you to win more at competition.
Or better yet,
I want to give you the confidence so
when you next go to
competition, you win.
And here's a promise.
If you don't podium in first place in a
competition within the next six months of
studying my course,
I will refund you in full." Suddenly,
the whole way this person
is thinking about their jiu-jitsu's
completely changed.
Yesterday when they woke up,
they hadn't dreamed of having a coach
that they use
online.
They even didn't even know the submission
they learnt from the
instructional. Now suddenly,
there's someone that they could actually
learn from,
they have learned from,
that's now telling them they can go win at
competition.
The next thing they're thinking is,
"How much is this going to cost me?"
And that
can apply to any realm or field
or whatever it is.
You could be a lawyer breaking down
marital law to get people clued up
if they're going through a divorce.
You could be a soccer coach breaking down
the essential drills that are essential
for you to do certain things in
that sport.
And it's only through the acquisition of
getting someone to your email list that
you can partially indoctrinate them to
wanting to do business with you.
Indoctrinate's the wrong word,
but you know what I mean.
So that's number two.
The third one would to be getting to this
autoresponder.
You don't have to write all these emails
manually.
For instance, I have an email list
that I've written four months of emails,
each
one delivering a helpful fact
and trick and tip
when it comes to nutrition
to help people lose fat, get in shape,
whatever.
All they need to do is sign them up.
And again, over that four-month period of
time, I guarantee, and the data shows,
that a lot of people join
that just because
they want the value from the emails.
But over the course of months of being
helped every day,
they're getting warmed up,
as we use in sales terminology.
They start as a co-Cold lead
and the automations
day by day warm them up to the point
they're like, "Do you know what?
This guy's turned up for me every single
day with a tip.
He's obviously pre-written these emails
for months.
I'm going to join his program because no
one else is." Again, these autoresponders
could be to do with anything. Even if,
let's say, you're a judo instructor
and you
recorded a course on the uchi mata,
which is a type of
throw for any of you not in jujitsu.
You can then be like, "Hey, guys.
I've got an instructional here to help you
with hip throws.
Every day you'll get emailed a certain tip
or trick or setup, whatever it
is.
It's completely free." Then over those
days, they could get all of that value
by email, and on the last day you go,
"Look, I've actually put this all into a
course,
and I've saved the best bits for it.
It's only X amount.
Buy now." If you were to teach languages,
you could say, "Over the next 100 days,
I'm going to teach you 100 things
that you can do to speak French,
not fluently,
but to the level that
when you next go to France
or a French-speaking country,
you'll be able to navigate the world of
speaking a foreign language." Oh, cool,
it's free as well.
Then those people start learning little
bits of French over that
100 days, and then before they know it,
they're at a restaurant.
"Oh, [foreign language] ."
And they're like,
"Wow." Then they get engaged.
If you would like to speak French
fluently, I have an online course.
It'll take you three to six months,
and it costs this.
They go, "Oh, do you know what?
I'm already one foot in."
And this doesn't have to
be everyone. If 100 people join your list,
if five buy, it's better than the ratios
you would get them from sending them to
the website.
Then number four, another thing
that I think you should do
is some kind of smaller
course,
and I'll use jujitsu as an example.
Everyone sells instructionals that are 10,
15 hours.
I don't think anyone's cracked the market
of 10, 15-minute instructionals.
Similarly to if you were
that language teacher, again,
you could teach
someone how to speak French
when going on a walk,
and you would only talk
about things as how to say, "Where
is something? How do I find...?
Can you please help me?" You could just
talk about random things.
A very small course, and
that course could be £10, $10.
For instance, with my online program,
in the links in the description,
you'll see
that my main course, the daddy course,
is there, but then I've created smaller
courses for $99 US. And the idea is
that people do the smaller course because
they
just want to put a foot in.
And from there,
you can upgrade people into the big
course,
or you could just keep them in the small
course, or you can even make
really, really small courses.
So I did another course for a dollar,
so that when
people get that value of the small course,
they're more likely to buy the big one.
So what I'm saying is,
if you're someone
that sells BJJ instructionals for a few
hundred dollars and they're hours long,
you need to make a very, very short one.
And you can make a 10-minute
instructional,
either give it away for an email
address,
or maybe do a 20-minute instructional
and sell it for a dollar.
The statistical chances of me buying your
full course are hugely
higher once I've bought one before.
Think of it this way.
When you buy a car from a local
dealership,
what is the statistical chances you're
going to go back to
that same dealership and buy another car?
Much higher because of the experience you
had with the first time.
It's that trust barrier.
Same with a restaurant.
You go try out a new coffee shop.
If it's rubbish, you're never going back.
But if it's really good,
you're going to always go there.
Even if you're a fitness coach,
maybe you put together
an air fryer recipe guide for free to get
people's email addresses.
But then you go, "Hey, guys.
Off the back of that, here's 15
recipes that are between five
and 700 calories
that have 50 grams of protein in.
It's only $5.99." You sell it at $5.99.
You're not actually making
that much money on it.
But then they bought a product from you,
and it's excelled.
It's been better than what they thought.
It's like, "Oh my God, I only paid $5.99.
I got all these amazing recipes." So
when you upsell into coaching, they go,
"Well,
every experience with every product I had
before was great, so therefore I think
it's going to be great again." Then after
the smaller course, again, engage by
email, upsell, send them to the website.
Number five would be some kind of
resource.
So think about your demographic
and what it is that they're struggling
with.
If it was in the content creation space,
you could create a resource for how to get
fantastic audio.
Because even right now for this,
you can see there's a microphone
in front of me,
although it's kind of blended in with my
top.
But you don't know that this
is a Shure SM7B and
that you need an XLR cable that
goes into a Rodecaster,
technically a Rodecaster II,
so then I didn't need a
Cloudlifter to get clean audio gain,
and then that needs to be powered and then
connected into the computer.
That's very overwhelming for a lot of
content
creators. But if I
was to create a free resource, "Hey, guys.
Give me your..." This could actually be a
good idea I might put together.
"Give me your email address,
and I'm going to teach you how to create
an audio
setup to make your audio sound so crisp
that people wonder how you did it." That
actually could be great. I might use
that this afternoon.
I might run a paid ad on
that [chuckles] and start getting emails
for the course.
Give people a resource that can help.
Maybe even a brief editing,
how to use Premiere Pro for noobs.
"Hey, guys. Give me your email address,
and I'm going to teach you and send you a
resource on how to use Premiere Pro."
Deadlift resource, whatever it is.
If you can think of ways
that you can just help someone and
that you can do it for
free in exchange for their email address,
you can then win that person over,
fantastic resource,
send them to the website.
Something that I use
are calorie calculators.
I have a 30-day email responder, which
is also kind of like a resource lead
magnet.
And another one of those
is the free trial to my online coaching
platform.
It's my online coaching platform,
Affordable Online Coaching.
We give people a free week, and
that costs us money,
but we acquire the person's
email address. So the majority of people,
let's say we get 100
people trial our program.
Let's say 15 of them
buy. We've now got 75, 85,
good maths, people that didn't buy.
We don't just ignore them.
We bring them into another email campaign
called Trialed Never Purchased.
And although that person's cost me like
£10, for the price of their email address,
it's great because I can now engage them,
and I can engage them knowing that
they've downloaded the app,
and I can talk to them in a slightly
different way.
So that free trial in some respects
is a resource.
And the resource transfer
was they got a free workout
and access to the app for a
week, and in exchange,
I got their email address,
so I can now communicate with
them to upsell them into the program.
Number six.
Another reason why email would be better
than going to the website is to give
someone an offer or to reengage them.
So again,
if someone did buy your product
or did buy your services and maybe they
left or discontinued, email
is a great way to reengage that person.
"Hey, Sam.
I know you finished training with me six
months ago. How's everything looking?
Are you still keeping up with attending
the gym?
Would you like to consider training with
me again?" Reengaging old clients.
"Hey,
I know that you did my business
mentorship,
but now I've created a high-tier
exclusive community." I'm just making this
up.
"Would you like to be involved?" Even
when I bought my parents a Porsche last
2021, I get emails from Porsche. "Hey,
James.
As a valued customer,
we wanted to give you first dibs on the
new 992.2
allocation of the 911." Whatever it is.
They say there's three ways to grow a
business.
Get new clients,
get your existing clients to buy more from
you, and get your
existing clients to buy more frequently
from you.
So two thirds of growing your business sit
within the existing database that you
already have.
And kind of number seven on this,
I actually had a bit of a
moan to the guys at Nutonix the other day.
So we're running a Black Friday
initiative. It's 20% off.
20% off everything. And they said,
"We'll only give 20% off to people that
join our Subscribe
and Save." So in essence, they sign up
and get recurring
deliveries of the product
that they could save 20% off.
I'm like, "Nah." I'm like, "Guys,
we've got this all wrong." The likeliness
of
someone not just buying for the first
time, buying for the first time and
subscribing, it's too much.
Too many barriers to entry.
And the concern is
that at our Black Friday discount of 20%
off, our
margins are so thin
that it's almost not even worth it
unless they become a subscribing customer,
because then with every purchase they
run in, we can recoup their costs.
And let's say that the average person on
a subscription stays for a year,
we would have to 12 times the profit
margin at
20% discount. But I said, "Guys,
stop thinking of it like that.
The product's great. If someone joins
or someone buys it, even not on a
subscription,
they're going to have repeat purchases.
And even if they don't,
I'm sure enough people will." And again,
I said, "Guys,
even if we were to sell NooTonic at no
margin, or even if we were
to lose 5% per case in Black Friday,
that's fine because
we can get their email address.
Because even if they don't buy over the
next two,
three months, we can reengage them. 'Hey,
how was the crate of NooTonic?
Hey, we saw you ordered 24 cans.
It's been 24 days.
Would you like a restock?
Hey,
we've seen you had the brain capsules.
It's been a month.
Would you like to leave us a review?
And whilst we're here,
would you like another order?'" Then they
get another order.
Then maybe after people have had two
orders, concurrently,
we can then engage them
for the Subscribe and Save. "Hey,
we've seen that you repeat purchase our
product.
How would you like to be discounted for
doing that? Click here.
Become a Subscribe
and Save member." There have to be stages
to it, but all of
these have to occur via email. If I
was to do a video, "Hey, guys, if you
subscribe to NooTonic,
and you get a weekly delivery." If I
try putting that as a reel
or an Instagram story,
it's just going to bomb.
But if you can put it via email to the
right amount of people, it can be a hugely
effective campaign.
I inquired for a property the other day
online.
You know that a lot of properties,
when you're looking at houses,
they don't show
you the price.
You have to see how much they want for it,
and then they tell you.
You go, "Oh, Jesus Christ,
that's a lot of money."
But then they engage me to send
me off-market opportunities. "Hi, James.
There's a house off-market opportunity
nearby your area.
Owners are wondering what you'd be
interested in putting down." Again, then
estate agents in the area can then
engage people that they know
are super hot red leads, people
that buy houses,
people that are in the market, people
that are interested,
and engage them to come
and look at the property.
It makes them feel special as well.
"Hey, James, we know
that this property could be within your
range and your
budget.
Would you like to come have a private
look?" Again, engaging people by
email.
Because you can segment your email list to
all different parts of
demographics, people that have bought,
people that haven't bought, people
that went
to look at a house but then didn't buy,
people that are proactively looking,
people
that bought a house two years ago
and could be looking to upsell, downsell,
whatever it is. And again, another reason,
point nine would be the
advertising effect, where
when people over the years spend a lot in
paid
advertising, it's not
that someone sees the advert for the first
time and goes,
"Oh,
I'm going to buy." Some people have to see
that advert 20, 30, 40, 50
times before they purchase.
The same way that sometimes you might need
to email
someone for months promoting your offer
before they finally crack.
And it's not like Chinese water torture
that you're forcing them.
"You buy the product." It's
that they just might need to be reminded a
certain
amount of times.
You might need to drive past a car
dealership a finite amount of
times before you go, "Jesus Christ,
I'm going in.
I'm test driving
that car." You might have to see an advert
online for
GoCompare or comparethemarket.com,
and then when you go to do your car
insurance,
you're like,
"I'm going to go Compare the Market." Why?
Because it's all I've seen and heard.
So by having someone in an email list
and consistently delivering value to that
person, eventually, your product
or your offering is going to become a
household name in their mind.
And number 10, the most important thing,
I've always
called this the right time effect.
So if you're someone like me
that helps people make money online,
there's going to
be a day that someone's watching a video
just like this, and they've lost three
clients in a day. It's December,
they've lost three clients.
That's a tenth of their business.
They know that they need to really up
their
marketing game. They go, "James,
do you know what? Fuck it.
I'm buying your course." Again,
someone might be reading your emails kind
of
wanting to lose weight. "Yeah,
I could do with a PT.
Yeah,
I could do with a fitness trainer." Boom.
Girlfriend dumps them.
They go, "I'm getting a PT.
I'm getting in shape.
I'm getting sexy." Other way around.
Woman goes to work.
Her jeans button pops off
when she sits down. Email comes through.
James Smith, Affordable Online Coaching.
She goes, "I'm in.
I'm never having this happen to me again."
And if you're not consistent with that,
again, Luke, Sydney Wess,
the jujitsu opportunity.
If you go to competition
and lose all your matches,
you get an email the next day
promoting Sydney Wess Online.
[chuckles] "I'm in.
I need this." But if you're not persistent
and consistent with turning up with your
marketing, because again, in anything,
if you don't turn up and you're not
consistent with posting content,
you don't grow your following.
If you don't turn up to jujitsu,
you don't get any better.
If you don't turn up every single day
and be consistent,
you're never going to be
that successful.
And the same goes with outbound.
As long as you can keep the emails of
value to that person, and again,
golden rule
is you can never send too many emails.
You can only be too boring.
You're going to get the right time effect,
and all those 10 examples should back
that up. And the best part of that
is right now it's December.
Not many of us are going to be making huge
amounts of sales over this next period
of months because it's December.
People are disengaging from pretty much
everything
in the wind-up to Christmas. This
is a perfect opportunity to go through a
phase of planting seeds through your
content, and I would say the harvesting
process should be getting email addresses
from people.
Getting someone to buy your product on
December 22nd, probably quite hard.
But getting someone's email address,
not that difficult.
So if you can see December as a period in
time for whatever your business is to get
as much data and as many emails as you
can.
Let's say you were to get 100 emails
or 1,000 emails or 100,000
emails. Come January 1st, you smash
that list.
So your list degrades by 10%, 20%, 30%,
40%, 50%.
You send so many emails,
the email list halves.
Do you know what I say? Good.
Because if you half your email list from
outbound marketing emails, let me tell you
this, your client list
is going to grow at the same time.
I've got friends with massive email lists
that are scared to email them.
I'm like,
"What's the point?" Because once you can
create systems on social media
where you put out content that does well,
and then you can put out call to actions
that work and that grow your email list,
you go through planting the crops,
harvesting the crops. Client lists go up,
email list goes down.
You go through peaks and troughs.
Growing your list, harvesting your list.
Growing your socials,
harvesting your socials.
But the worst thing you can do
is to expect people on social media to go
straight
to your website and buy.
It just bypasses all the psychology of how
the sales
process works in dating, anywhere.
Get them on your email list.
From there,
point them in the direction of your
website because then they'll click
on your website when they're ready,
when they have had the emotional
investment
through you, your brand,
and your offering,
and you'll catch them on the day
they're ready to buy.
So don't go up to people
and ask them to come home to suck
your dick. Because 1 in 100 will,
and it'll make you think it works.
Instead, get their number,
qualify them out, go on loads of dates,
get your dick
sucked that way. As per usual,
YouTube's probably going to put a video up
here they
recommend, if you watch it,
it'll change your life,
make your life better.
And as per usual,
there'll be links in the description.
Speak to you guys in a bit.
Bye-bye.